

Pura, Hebron, Palestine

(+970) 0569638068

□ ayman201266@hotmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/amin-talahmeh/

github.com/ameentalahmeh

Summary

I've strong experience in many IT areas as Web Development, Mobile Programming, Artificial Intelligence, Information Retrieval, and Cloud Computing. Besides, I have hands-on experience with remote work as a Back-end Developer and Full-stack Developer for a long term period.

Education

Master - Computer Science

10/2017 - 06/2020

Arab American University, Palestine

Bachelor - Computer Systems Engineering

09/2012 - 07/2017

Palestine Polytechnic University

Work experience

Software Developer

06/2021 - Present

AHL Logics

- Specialized in Engineering and Domains fields.
- Build systems that are extremely scalable, available, fault-tolerant, concurrent, and easy to develop and maintain via combining event-driven architecture (EDA) and microservices architectural styles.
- Using Kafka as an event streaming system between microservices.
- o Using RedisDB as short term Cache for microservices.
- Using Docker for building, run and deploying images/services in containers.
- Using HashiCorp tools:
 - Nomad (Deploying services).
 - Consul (Services Discovering).
 - Vault (Secrets management).
 - Terraform (Setup systems infrastructure resources).
- o Build unit and integration tests.
- Experience with Saltstack for software management.
- Experience with observation and tracing tools like Grafana, Prometheus, Kibana, Elasticsearch, Alertmanager, and Jaeger.
- o Experience with Git, Github, and Linux OS.
- o Experience with creating diagrams using Lucidchart.
- Used Technologies: Python (Asyncio library), HCL, Jinja, PostgreSQL, and ReactJs.

Backend Developer

12/2020 - 06/2021

KeplerWorx Palestine

- o Develop REST API for travel agent app using AWS.
- Remote and Part-time work.
- Used Technologies: NodeJs, and AWS (Lambda, API Gateway, and DynamoDB)

Full-stack Web Developer

10/2019 - 06/2020

Kayan Healthcare Technologies

- o Create Healthcare solutions.
- Develop and deploy APIs and web services within Security, High Quality and Performance, and Simplicity in usage and integration.
- o Design and customize responsive apps for most platforms.
- o Embedded Al applications on our projects.
- o Remote work.
- Used Technologies: ReactJS, NodeJS, PostgreSQL, and Python.

Gaza Sky Geeks

- Full-Stack JS coding Bootcamp
- o Developing websites via ReactJS, NodeJS, and PostgreSQL technologies.
- Deploying websites to **Heroku** and **Netlify.**
- o using Git and Github.
- o Working within test-driven development (TDD), Agile methodologies, and pair programming.
- o Volunteer as a mentor for the next cohort.

Internships

Python Internship

Location: RemoteInstitution: DyNotify, Inc.Period: 01/2021 - 02/2021.

o Description: The internship includes developing Rest APIs by Python (FastAPI).

Freelancing Academy Internship

o Location: Remote

Institution: Gaza Sky GeeksPeriod: 07/2020 - 10/2020.

• **Description:** The academy includes training on how to be a freelancer on the best freelancing platforms (Upwork, Freelancer, People Per Hour, Mostaql, etc).

IT Internship

o Location: PS - Hebron

o Institution: IT and Software Home

Period: 02/2017 - 04/2017

• **Description:** The internship includes training on:

■ E-Marketing

■ Mobile Apps Development: **Android**.

Portfolio

Inventory Management Application

- o Location: Remote
- · Used Technologies: Python (Flask), ReactJS, Material Design for Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, and MySQL.
- URL: Inventory Management Application
- **Description:** A web app based on React and Flask, which is an inventory management application that enables the user to manage the inventory of a list of products in the respective warehouses.

Enums in languages

- o Location: Remote
- Used Technologies: HTML, CSS, JS, NodeJS and Cosmos Db (Azure Function Apps).
- URL: Enums in Languages
- **Description:** An azure function app allows the user to generate many enumerations (e.g. Day, Month, etc...) depending on the language (e.g. Arabic, English, French). Besides, the user can check if the enumeration contains a value with a given enumeration-value code, according to data stored in the cosmos database.

GoogleNa (Domain Specific Search Engine).

- o Location: PS Jenin.
- **Used Technologies:** Python, HTML, CSS, and JQuery.
- Description: GoogleNa is a Python-based search engine that's developed from scratch based on the Django framework and linked with UI that is designed using HTML and styled using CSS. The project includes many libraries (NTLK to enable the word stemming, requests, os, JSON, re, and others).

Great British Money Quiz

- o Location: UK London
- **Used Technologies:** ReactJS, ExpressJS, and MongoDB.
- o URL: Great British Money Quiz
- **Description:** A web app to test kids' financial knowledge level before giving them 5 days of training, and then, test their level again. The level testing is done by multiple-choice quizzes.

YDRC Reservation System

- o Location: PS Hebron
- Used Technologies: ReactJS, ExpressJS, and SequelizeJS.
- URL: YDRC Reservation System
- Description: A web app that enables YDRC administrators to arrange the reservation process in their organizations.

Skills

General

- o Experience with Rest APIs using Postman, JSON, and XML.
- o Experience with Database Management Systems.
- Dealing with hosting and deployment platforms like Heroku and Netfilv.
- Experience with version control systems like Git, Github, Gitlab, and Bitbucket.

- Dealing with the Linux environment.
- ∘ Coding in MVP & MVC design patterns.
- Experience with design tools such as Figma.
- Familiarity with team communication tools like Slack, Zoom, and Teamviewer.
- o MS Office Applications (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, and Access).
- o Writing good-designed Software documents.

Web Development

- o Frontend:
 - ReactJS
 - HTML5, CSS3, JS, JQuery
 - Responsive UI (CSS-Flexible, UI Material, Material Design for Bootstrap)
- o Backend:
 - NodeJS
 - ExpressJS (JavaScript MVC Framework)
 - Flask
 - FastAPI
 - Django
- o Database:
 - PostgreSQL
 - MySQL
 - SequelizeJS

Mobile Development

React Native

Cloud Computing

- Azure
- o AWS

AI and Information Retrieval

- Python (Search engine)
- Matlab (Prediction Systems)

| Programming | PythonC++ |
|-------------|----------------------------------------------------|
| Research | WritingAnalyzing (SPSS) |

Personal Skills

- $\circ \ \, {\rm Time \ management.}$
- o Goals orientated.
- Ability to grasp concepts quickly.
- Remote work.
- o Teamwork.

Languages

- Arabic
 - Native
- English
 - Excellent